https://pujeethaaj.github.io/ linkedin.com/in/pujeethaajakka/

SUMMARY

Experience in Data sciences & Data Analytics

Special focus on customer facing applications

Good at turning data into actionable insights

Strong Analytical and Problem-solving skills

Strategic Planner with technical expertise

Strong data-visualization and story-telling skills

Product manager with strong leadership skills

Experience in Machine Learning

Good at querying large databases

Good at generating new ideas

Self-motivated team player

Good at writing user stories

EDUCATION

University of Illinois, Urbana-Champaign, IL

GPA 4.0/4.0

Master of Science, School of Information sciences, December 2019

SASTRA University, Thanjavur, India

GPA 3.8/4.0

Bachelor of Technology, Bioinformatics Engineering

ACADEMIC

Data Mining, Data Visualization, Data warehousing & Business intelligence, Machine Learning, Statistics, Applied Business Research, Socio-Technical Info systems, Information Modelling, Information Consulting, Data Science Story Telling, Database Design & Prototyping, Business Data Modelling and Predictive Analytics.

PROJECTS

Analyzing cancer trends using Tableau

- > Analyzed the worldwide and US-wide cancer data to understand the Incidence and Mortality trends.
- ➤ Visualized the cancer picture Worldwide (Top 5 countries with the highest rates of cancer prevalence & mortality), USA (Top 5 states with the most life-threatening cancers)
- > Visualized a forecast of cancer trends and reasoned the increasing/decreasing trends.
- > Studied the correlation between cancer and annual income of different countries.

Analyzing and Visualizing the shoes of men and women using Python

- Using Python's matplotlib, bqplot, and ipywidgets, analyzed the most popular brands of shoes among men and women.
- Visualized
 - o The average price of the 15 most popular brands for Men and Women
 - Price distribution by Gender
 - o Most popular colors
 - o Price distribution by color

Analysis of air pollution levels and its contributing factors using Machine Learning models

- Worked with Beijing City's pollution data.
- ➤ Used various machine learning models to predict the particulate matter(pm2.5) value taking the wind speed, temperature, wind direction, date, and time as the predictor variables.
- Discovered an interesting pattern in the outlier data and analyzed it further to understand the data's revelation.
- Achieved an RMSE score of around 20 21

Movie recommendation System using collaborative filtering

- Applied collaborative filtering to a dataset of movie ratings.
- Predicted the movie ratings for movies that users had not yet rated.
- ➤ This helped to recommend movies with highest predicted ratings to the user.

SKILLS

Programming SQL, Python, R, Java

Visualization Tools/LibrariesTableau, Power BI, Scikit-learn, ggplot, Tibco SpotfireProduct Management/ToolsSlack, Jira, Asana, Business Objects, Weka, Rattle, MS Office

Web Technologies HTML5, JSON, XML, CSS

EXPERIENCE

Data Visualization and Communication Intern (Product Mgmt) – Bayer May 2019 – August 2019

- > SoyDash is the Product. SoyDash is a one-stop dashboard to track various stages of soy seed production from planting to packing
- > Collaborated with multiple stakeholders across business units to understand functional requirements
- Queried large databases using SQL to extract, transform the data & to track the operational touchpoints
- Built visualization by extracting data from different sources to enable stakeholders find insights
- Enabled planning & logistics team in early issue detection and overall better communication among the teams. #Spotfire #SQL #R #Jira

Strategic Operations Consultant – Illinois Business Consulting

- ➤ Illinois Business Consulting is the largest professionally-managed, student-run university consulting organization in the country
- Learning and Development team develop RAMP (Rotation and Mentorship program), training and Knowledge management resources for the incoming fall consultants, project managers at IBC
- Knowledge Management expert on the team

Graduate Assistant - University of Illinois, Urbana Champaign

October 2018 - Present

➤ Tutor/Grader for CS598/IS531 – Foundation Data curation & BADM 590 - Predictive analytics.

Consultant - Business Intelligence Group [BIG]

- Provided Knowledge Management Service to a Student Consulting organization at UIUC.
- ➤ Helped them manage their intellectual assets by providing technological solutions
- Developed Organizational policies and structure to embed Knowledge Management Process into the organizational structure
- Promoted to Senior Consultant

Product Manager & Founder - ImpressionsInfinite

January 2017 - December 2018

> Hoardapenny is the product and it is a real time deals web app that provides best deals by scraping web content, ingesting it to a scalable index, notify subscribers top rated deals. #elasticsearch #pwa #cloud

Data Analyst (Project Lead) - Wipro Technologies

Client: Banking & Financial Industry

- > Identified potential high value customers in different regions to cross sell different products
- Generated insights on different promotions (Measure impact and ROI) by slicing and dicing data
- Discovered and analyzed interesting patterns hidden in the data
- > Built interactive dashboards in Tableau from different sources of data for all stakeholders to use
- Mentored and managed a team of 3 data analysts #Tableau #PivotTable #SQLServer

Software Engineer in Test - Wipro Technologies

- > Built one-stop monitoring dashboard to monitor the performance of various services like Eclipse Greet and SAO Greet, Citi planner etc and send test automation reports in an email.
- > Automated environment health check process in QTP using **VB script**.

Central Leather Research Institute - Research Analyst - Intern

Molecular Modelling of the Interactions between the Mismatch Repair Proteins

- Modelled and Analyzed the interactions between the MMR proteins failing in repairing a mismatch occurring during replication which might cause Cancer using MATLAB and MS Excel.
- ➤ Identified a suitable template based on sequence similarity for the 26 different organisms that were selected & modeled their structures.
- > Visualized using Pymol to identify the interacting residues which are potential targets for drug designing.

CERTIFICATES

Machine Learning - Coursera, Stanford University - License MUJ8UJ2Z2QGN

Managing BIG DATA with MySQL - Coursera, Duke University

Data Visualization & Communication with Tableau - Coursera, Duke University

Project Management: Solving Common Project Problems – LinkedIn

Product Management: Building a Product Strategy - LinkedIn

PORTFOLIO

Visualization: https://public.tableau.com/profile/pujeethaa.jakka#!/

HONORS

"Prodigy Award" - Wipro Technologies, Chennai, India

"Topper in Mathematics" – SASTRA University & Bhaktavatsalam Vidyashram High School, India

"Best Paper Award"- "Application of Data Mining" – PRATYARTH 2009, SASTRA University –India.

"Bronze Medal"- "International Award for young people"

VOLUNTEERING

Conducted Arts and crafts classes for kids at Kent Hindu Temple at Kent, WA during festivals every year. Student Placement Coordinator, Department of Bioinformatics Engineering, SASTRA 2010.